var words = 
[
    {
        "question": "آبَائِكُمُ",
        "answer": "(of) your fathers",
        "pcklId": "58",
        "rootWordId": 10,
        "tlit": "ābāikumu",
        "frequency": "117",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ يُحْيِي وَيُمِيتُ رَبُّكُمْ وَرَبُّ آبَائِكُمُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ب و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آبَاء",
        "waznEnglish": "forefathers, fathers, parents",
        "waznTlit": "ābā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِآبَائِنَا",
        "answer": "our forefathers",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 10,
        "tlit": "biābāinā",
        "frequency": "117",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأْتُوا بِآبَائِنَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ب و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آبَاء",
        "waznEnglish": "forefathers, fathers, parents",
        "waznTlit": "ābā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَأْتِي",
        "answer": "(when) will bring",
        "pcklId": "234",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "tatī",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَارْتَقِبْ يَوْمَ تَأْتِي السَّمَاءُ بِدُخَانٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to come, to bring",
        "waznTlit": "atā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "آتِيكُمْ",
        "answer": "[I] have come to you",
        "pcklId": "235",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "ātīkum",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْ لَا تَعْلُوا عَلَى اللَّهِ إِنِّي آتِيكُمْ بِسُلْطَانٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to come, to bring",
        "waznTlit": "atā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأْتُوا",
        "answer": "Then bring",
        "pcklId": "236",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "fatū",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأْتُوا بِآبَائِنَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to come, to bring",
        "waznTlit": "atā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَآتَيْنَاهُمْ",
        "answer": "And We gave them",
        "pcklId": "495",
        "rootWordId": 12,
        "tlit": "waātaynāhum",
        "frequency": "549",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَآتَيْنَاهُمْ مِنَ الْآيَاتِ مَا فِيهِ بَلَاءٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ ت ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آتَى",
        "waznEnglish": "to give",
        "waznTlit": "ātā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَثِيمِ",
        "answer": "(of) the sinner(s)",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 16,
        "tlit": "l-athīmi",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " طَعَامُ الْأَثِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "أ ث م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَثِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "sinful",
        "waznTlit": "athīm",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "خُذُوهُ",
        "answer": "Seize him",
        "pcklId": "111",
        "rootWordId": 21,
        "tlit": "khudhūhu",
        "frequency": "273",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " خُذُوهُ فَاعْتِلُوهُ إِلَىٰ سَوَاءِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ذ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخَذَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to take, to seize",
        "waznTlit": "akhadha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "آخَرِينَ",
        "answer": "another",
        "pcklId": "246",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "ākharīna",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ وَأَوْرَثْنَاهَا قَوْمًا آخَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخَر",
        "waznEnglish": "other, last",
        "waznTlit": "ākhar",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَدُّوا",
        "answer": "Deliver",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 25,
        "tlit": "addū",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ أَدُّوا إِلَيَّ عِبَادَ اللَّهِ إِنِّي لَكُمْ رَسُولٌ أَمِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُؤَدِّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to discharge, to deliver",
        "waznTlit": "yu-addi",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأَرْضِ",
        "answer": "and the earth",
        "pcklId": "379",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "wal-arḍi",
        "frequency": "461",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ مُوقِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأَرْضُ",
        "answer": "and the earth",
        "pcklId": "380",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "wal-arḍu",
        "frequency": "461",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا بَكَتْ عَلَيْهِمُ السَّمَاءُ وَالْأَرْضُ وَمَا كَانُوا مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأَرْضَ",
        "answer": "and the earth",
        "pcklId": "381",
        "rootWordId": 32,
        "tlit": "wal-arḍa",
        "frequency": "461",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقْنَا السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا لَاعِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ر ض",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ر ض",
        "waznEnglish": "the Earth, land",
        "waznTlit": "hamza rā ḍād",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَإِسْتَبْرَقٍ",
        "answer": "and heavy silk",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 38,
        "tlit": "wa-is'tabraqin",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "53",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَلْبَسُونَ مِنْ سُنْدُسٍ وَإِسْتَبْرَقٍ مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِسْتَبْرَق",
        "rootWordType": "noun",
        "wazn": "إِسْتَبْرَق",
        "waznEnglish": "brocade, heavy silk",
        "waznTlit": "is'tabraq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِسْرَائِيلَ",
        "answer": "(the) Children of Israel",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 41,
        "tlit": "is'rāīla",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ نَجَّيْنَا بَنِي إِسْرَائِيلَ مِنَ الْعَذَابِ الْمُهِينِ",
        "rootWord": "إِسْرَائِيل",
        "rootWordType": "proper noun",
        "wazn": "إِسْرَائِيل",
        "waznEnglish": "Israel",
        "waznTlit": "is'rāīl",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "482",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ يُحْيِي وَيُمِيتُ رَبُّكُمْ وَرَبُّ آبَائِكُمُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "(is) but",
        "pcklId": "483",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هِيَ إِلَّا مَوْتَتُنَا الْأُولَىٰ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمُنْشَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "but",
        "pcklId": "484",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا خَلَقْنَاهُمَا إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ وَلَٰكِنَّ أَكْثَرَهُمْ لَا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "Except",
        "pcklId": "485",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ رَحِمَ اللَّهُ إِنَّهُ هُوَ الْعَزِيزُ الرَّحِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَّا",
        "answer": "except",
        "pcklId": "486",
        "rootWordId": 58,
        "tlit": "illā",
        "frequency": "663",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَذُوقُونَ فِيهَا الْمَوْتَ إِلَّا الْمَوْتَةَ الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَّا",
        "rootWordType": "particle",
        "wazn": "إِلَّا",
        "waznEnglish": "except",
        "waznTlit": "illā",
        "waznType": "Particle (Restriction particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالَّذِينَ",
        "answer": "and those",
        "pcklId": "1189",
        "rootWordId": 59,
        "tlit": "wa-alladhīna",
        "frequency": "1464",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " أَهُمْ خَيْرٌ أَمْ قَوْمُ تُبَّعٍ وَالَّذِينَ مِنْ قَبْلِهِمْ",
        "rootWord": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "ٱلَّذِى",
        "waznEnglish": "who, which, that",
        "waznTlit": "alladhī",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Relative pronoun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَلِيمٌ",
        "answer": "painful",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 60,
        "tlit": "alīmun",
        "frequency": "75",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَغْشَى النَّاسَ هَٰذَا عَذَابٌ أَلِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَلِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "painful",
        "waznTlit": "alīm",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَٰهَ",
        "answer": "god",
        "pcklId": "133",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "ilāha",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ يُحْيِي وَيُمِيتُ رَبُّكُمْ وَرَبُّ آبَائِكُمُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِلَٰه",
        "waznEnglish": "god",
        "waznTlit": "ilāh",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "(of) Allah",
        "pcklId": "2422",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ أَدُّوا إِلَيَّ عِبَادَ اللَّهِ إِنِّي لَكُمْ رَسُولٌ أَمِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهِ",
        "answer": "Allah",
        "pcklId": "2423",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahi",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْ لَا تَعْلُوا عَلَى اللَّهِ إِنِّي آتِيكُمْ بِسُلْطَانٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّهُ",
        "answer": "Allah has mercy",
        "pcklId": "2424",
        "rootWordId": 61,
        "tlit": "l-lahu",
        "frequency": "2851",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ رَحِمَ اللَّهُ إِنَّهُ هُوَ الْعَزِيزُ الرَّحِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ل ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱللَّه",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah",
        "waznTlit": "allah",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَيَّ",
        "answer": "to me",
        "pcklId": "627",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilayya",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ أَدُّوا إِلَيَّ عِبَادَ اللَّهِ إِنِّي لَكُمْ رَسُولٌ أَمِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "into",
        "pcklId": "628",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " خُذُوهُ فَاعْتِلُوهُ إِلَىٰ سَوَاءِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْ",
        "answer": "or",
        "pcklId": "94",
        "rootWordId": 66,
        "tlit": "am",
        "frequency": "137",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَهُمْ خَيْرٌ أَمْ قَوْمُ تُبَّعٍ وَالَّذِينَ مِنْ قَبْلِهِمْ",
        "rootWord": "أَم",
        "rootWordType": "coordinating conjunction",
        "wazn": "أَم",
        "waznEnglish": "or",
        "waznTlit": "am",
        "waznType": "Coordinating conjunction"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْرٍ",
        "answer": "affair",
        "pcklId": "215",
        "rootWordId": 69,
        "tlit": "amrin",
        "frequency": "248",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فِيهَا يُفْرَقُ كُلُّ أَمْرٍ حَكِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمْر",
        "waznEnglish": "command, affair, matter",
        "waznTlit": "amr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمْرًا",
        "answer": "A command",
        "pcklId": "216",
        "rootWordId": 69,
        "tlit": "amran",
        "frequency": "248",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْرًا مِنْ عِنْدِنَا إِنَّا كُنَّا مُرْسِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمْر",
        "waznEnglish": "command, affair, matter",
        "waznTlit": "amr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُؤْمِنُوا",
        "answer": "you believe",
        "pcklId": "460",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "tu'minū",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ لَمْ تُؤْمِنُوا لِي فَاعْتَزِلُونِ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَامَنَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to believe",
        "waznTlit": "āmana",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمِينٌ",
        "answer": "trustworthy",
        "pcklId": "581",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "amīnun",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ أَدُّوا إِلَيَّ عِبَادَ اللَّهِ إِنِّي لَكُمْ رَسُولٌ أَمِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "amīn",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمِينٍ",
        "answer": "secure",
        "pcklId": "582",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "amīnin",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "51",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُتَّقِينَ فِي مَقَامٍ أَمِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "amīn",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "آمِنِينَ",
        "answer": "secure",
        "pcklId": "600",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "āminīna",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "55",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَدْعُونَ فِيهَا بِكُلِّ فَاكِهَةٍ آمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ءَامِنِين",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "āminīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "answer": "(are) believers",
        "pcklId": "814",
        "rootWordId": 75,
        "tlit": "mu'minūna",
        "frequency": "879",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبَّنَا اكْشِفْ عَنَّا الْعَذَابَ إِنَّا مُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "أ م ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُؤْمِن",
        "waznEnglish": "you are secure",
        "waznTlit": "mu'min",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنَّىٰ",
        "answer": "How can",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 81,
        "tlit": "annā",
        "frequency": "36",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنَّىٰ لَهُمُ الذِّكْرَىٰ وَقَدْ جَاءَهُمْ رَسُولٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "come (the) time",
        "waznTlit": "annā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Interogative particle)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأُولَىٰ",
        "answer": "the first",
        "pcklId": "42",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-ūlā",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هِيَ إِلَّا مَوْتَتُنَا الْأُولَىٰ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمُنْشَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأُولَىٰ",
        "answer": "the first",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-ūlā",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَذُوقُونَ فِيهَا الْمَوْتَ إِلَّا الْمَوْتَةَ الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "answer": "the former",
        "pcklId": "76",
        "rootWordId": 85,
        "tlit": "l-awalīna",
        "frequency": "170",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " يُحْيِي وَيُمِيتُ رَبُّكُمْ وَرَبُّ آبَائِكُمُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "أ و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوَّل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) first",
        "waznTlit": "awwal",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآيَاتِ",
        "answer": "the Signs",
        "pcklId": "345",
        "rootWordId": 90,
        "tlit": "l-āyāti",
        "frequency": "382",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَآتَيْنَاهُمْ مِنَ الْآيَاتِ مَا فِيهِ بَلَاءٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ي ي",
        "waznEnglish": "Our Signs",
        "waznTlit": "hamza yā yā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبَحْرَ",
        "answer": "the sea",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 99,
        "tlit": "l-baḥra",
        "frequency": "42",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاتْرُكِ الْبَحْرَ رَهْوًا إِنَّهُمْ جُنْدٌ مُغْرَقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ح ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَحْر",
        "waznEnglish": "the sea",
        "waznTlit": "baḥr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُبَارَكَةٍ",
        "answer": "Blessed",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 118,
        "tlit": "mubārakatin",
        "frequency": "32",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَنْزَلْنَاهُ فِي لَيْلَةٍ مُبَارَكَةٍ إِنَّا كُنَّا مُنْذِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبَٰرَكَة",
        "waznEnglish": "We blessed",
        "waznTlit": "mubārakat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَبْطِشُ",
        "answer": "We will seize",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 134,
        "tlit": "nabṭishu",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ نَبْطِشُ الْبَطْشَةَ الْكُبْرَىٰ إِنَّا مُنْتَقِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ط ش",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَطَشْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to seize",
        "waznTlit": "baṭash",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبَطْشَةَ",
        "answer": "(with) the seizure",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 134,
        "tlit": "l-baṭshata",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ نَبْطِشُ الْبَطْشَةَ الْكُبْرَىٰ إِنَّا مُنْتَقِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ط ش",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَطْشَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(to) hold",
        "waznTlit": "baṭshat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبُطُونِ",
        "answer": "the bellies",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 136,
        "tlit": "l-buṭūni",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كَالْمُهْلِ يَغْلِي فِي الْبُطُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ط ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَطْن",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) concealed",
        "waznTlit": "baṭn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَكَتْ",
        "answer": "wept",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 153,
        "tlit": "bakat",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا بَكَتْ عَلَيْهِمُ السَّمَاءُ وَالْأَرْضُ وَمَا كَانُوا مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ك ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَكَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to weep",
        "waznTlit": "bakat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَلَاءٌ",
        "answer": "(was) a trial",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 158,
        "tlit": "balāon",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَآتَيْنَاهُمْ مِنَ الْآيَاتِ مَا فِيهِ بَلَاءٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَلَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "And surely We will test you",
        "waznTlit": "balā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَنِي",
        "answer": "(the) Children of Israel",
        "pcklId": "165",
        "rootWordId": 160,
        "tlit": "banī",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ نَجَّيْنَا بَنِي إِسْرَائِيلَ مِنَ الْعَذَابِ الْمُهِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بُنَىّ",
        "waznEnglish": "they built",
        "waznTlit": "buna",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَيْنَهُمَا",
        "answer": "(is) between both of them",
        "pcklId": "264",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "baynahumā",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ مُوقِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "bayn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَيْنَهُمَا",
        "answer": "(is) between them",
        "pcklId": "265",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "baynahumā",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقْنَا السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا لَاعِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "bayn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Location adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُبِينٍ",
        "answer": "visible",
        "pcklId": "463",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "mubīnin",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " فَارْتَقِبْ يَوْمَ تَأْتِي السَّمَاءُ بِدُخَانٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mubīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُبِينٌ",
        "answer": "clear",
        "pcklId": "464",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "mubīnun",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنَّىٰ لَهُمُ الذِّكْرَىٰ وَقَدْ جَاءَهُمْ رَسُولٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mubīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُبِينٍ",
        "answer": "clear",
        "pcklId": "465",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "mubīnin",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْ لَا تَعْلُوا عَلَى اللَّهِ إِنِّي آتِيكُمْ بِسُلْطَانٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mubīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُبِينٌ",
        "answer": "clear",
        "pcklId": "466",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "mubīnun",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " وَآتَيْنَاهُمْ مِنَ الْآيَاتِ مَا فِيهِ بَلَاءٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mubīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُبِينِ",
        "answer": "the clear",
        "pcklId": "513",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "l-mubīni",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْكِتَابِ الْمُبِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "mubīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُتَّبَعُونَ",
        "answer": "(will be) followed",
        "pcklId": "171",
        "rootWordId": 176,
        "tlit": "muttabaʿūna",
        "frequency": "172",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَسْرِ بِعِبَادِي لَيْلًا إِنَّكُمْ مُتَّبَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّتَّبَعُون",
        "waznEnglish": "follows",
        "waznTlit": "muttabaʿūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَاتْرُكِ",
        "answer": "And leave",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 182,
        "tlit": "wa-ut'ruki",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاتْرُكِ الْبَحْرَ رَهْوًا إِنَّهُمْ جُنْدٌ مُغْرَقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَرَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave",
        "waznTlit": "taraka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَرَكُوا",
        "answer": "(did) they leave",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 182,
        "tlit": "tarakū",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَمْ تَرَكُوا مِنْ جَنَّاتٍ وَعُيُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَرَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave",
        "waznTlit": "taraka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَحِيمِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Hellfire",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 227,
        "tlit": "l-jaḥīmi",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " خُذُوهُ فَاعْتِلُوهُ إِلَىٰ سَوَاءِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ح م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the blazing Fire",
        "waznTlit": "jīm ḥā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْجَحِيمِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Hellfire",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 227,
        "tlit": "l-jaḥīmi",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَذُوقُونَ فِيهَا الْمَوْتَ إِلَّا الْمَوْتَةَ الْأُولَىٰ وَوَقَاهُمْ عَذَابَ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ج ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ح م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) the blazing Fire",
        "waznTlit": "jīm ḥā mīm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُجْرِمُونَ",
        "answer": "criminals",
        "pcklId": "47",
        "rootWordId": 241,
        "tlit": "muj'rimūna",
        "frequency": "66",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " فَدَعَا رَبَّهُ أَنَّ هَٰؤُلَاءِ قَوْمٌ مُجْرِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُجْرِم",
        "waznEnglish": "incite you",
        "waznTlit": "muj'rim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُجْرِمِينَ",
        "answer": "criminals",
        "pcklId": "48",
        "rootWordId": 241,
        "tlit": "muj'rimīna",
        "frequency": "66",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "12",
        "arabicAyah": " أَهْلَكْنَاهُمْ إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا مُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُجْرِم",
        "waznEnglish": "incite you",
        "waznTlit": "muj'rim",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "answer": "all",
        "pcklId": "53",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "ajmaʿīna",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ يَوْمَ الْفَصْلِ مِيقَاتُهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَجْمَعِين",
        "waznEnglish": "We will gather them",
        "waznTlit": "ajmaʿīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "جُنْدٌ",
        "answer": "(are) an army",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 265,
        "tlit": "jundun",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاتْرُكِ الْبَحْرَ رَهْوًا إِنَّهُمْ جُنْدٌ مُغْرَقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ن د",
        "waznEnglish": "with the forces",
        "waznTlit": "jīm nūn dāl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَنَّاتٍ",
        "answer": "gardens",
        "pcklId": "94",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "jannātin",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كَمْ تَرَكُوا مِنْ جَنَّاتٍ وَعُيُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَنَّاتٍ",
        "answer": "gardens",
        "pcklId": "95",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "jannātin",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "52",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي جَنَّاتٍ وَعُيُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَنَّة",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "jannat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَجْنُونٌ",
        "answer": "a mad man",
        "pcklId": "193",
        "rootWordId": 267,
        "tlit": "majnūnun",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ تَوَلَّوْا عَنْهُ وَقَالُوا مُعَلَّمٌ مَجْنُونٌ",
        "rootWord": "ج ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَجْنُون",
        "waznEnglish": "covered",
        "waznTlit": "majnūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَاءَهُمْ",
        "answer": "had come to them",
        "pcklId": "241",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "jāahum",
        "frequency": "278",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنَّىٰ لَهُمُ الذِّكْرَىٰ وَقَدْ جَاءَهُمْ رَسُولٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجَاءَهُمْ",
        "answer": "and came to them",
        "pcklId": "242",
        "rootWordId": 281,
        "tlit": "wajāahum",
        "frequency": "278",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ فَتَنَّا قَبْلَهُمْ قَوْمَ فِرْعَوْنَ وَجَاءَهُمْ رَسُولٌ كَرِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ج ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ج ي أ",
        "waznEnglish": "to come",
        "waznTlit": "jīm yā hamza",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالْحَقِّ",
        "answer": "in [the] truth",
        "pcklId": "247",
        "rootWordId": 344,
        "tlit": "bil-ḥaqi",
        "frequency": "287",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا خَلَقْنَاهُمَا إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ وَلَٰكِنَّ أَكْثَرَهُمْ لَا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ق ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَقّ",
        "waznEnglish": "deserved ",
        "waznTlit": "ḥaqq",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "حَكِيمٍ",
        "answer": "wise",
        "pcklId": "171",
        "rootWordId": 345,
        "tlit": "ḥakīmin",
        "frequency": "210",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فِيهَا يُفْرَقُ كُلُّ أَمْرٍ حَكِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح ك م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَكِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "will judge",
        "waznTlit": "ḥakīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحَمِيمِ",
        "answer": "(of) scalding water",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 355,
        "tlit": "l-ḥamīmi",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَغَلْيِ الْحَمِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ح م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "boiling water",
        "waznTlit": "ḥamīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْحَمِيمِ",
        "answer": "(of) the scalding water",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 355,
        "tlit": "l-ḥamīmi",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ صُبُّوا فَوْقَ رَأْسِهِ مِنْ عَذَابِ الْحَمِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ح م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَمِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "boiling water",
        "waznTlit": "ḥamīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِحُورٍ",
        "answer": "(to) companions with beautiful eyes",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 367,
        "tlit": "biḥūrin",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "54",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ وَزَوَّجْنَاهُمْ بِحُورٍ عِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح و ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حُور",
        "waznEnglish": "he would return",
        "waznTlit": "ḥūr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُحْيِي",
        "answer": "He gives life",
        "pcklId": "52",
        "rootWordId": 381,
        "tlit": "yuḥ'yī",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ يُحْيِي وَيُمِيتُ رَبُّكُمْ وَرَبُّ آبَائِكُمُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَحْيَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to give life",
        "waznTlit": "aḥyā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقْنَا",
        "answer": "We created",
        "pcklId": "133",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqnā",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقْنَا السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا لَاعِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَلَقْنَاهُمَا",
        "answer": "We created both of them",
        "pcklId": "134",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "khalaqnāhumā",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا خَلَقْنَاهُمَا إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ وَلَٰكِنَّ أَكْثَرَهُمْ لَا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اخْتَرْنَاهُمْ",
        "answer": "We chose them",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 449,
        "tlit": "ikh'tarnāhum",
        "frequency": "196",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدِ اخْتَرْنَاهُمْ عَلَىٰ عِلْمٍ عَلَى الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "خ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱخْتَارَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to choose",
        "waznTlit": "ikh'tāra",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "خَيْرٌ",
        "answer": "better",
        "pcklId": "129",
        "rootWordId": 449,
        "tlit": "khayrun",
        "frequency": "196",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَهُمْ خَيْرٌ أَمْ قَوْمُ تُبَّعٍ وَالَّذِينَ مِنْ قَبْلِهِمْ",
        "rootWord": "خ ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "they select",
        "waznTlit": "khayr",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِدُخَانٍ",
        "answer": "smoke",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 462,
        "tlit": "bidukhānin",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَارْتَقِبْ يَوْمَ تَأْتِي السَّمَاءُ بِدُخَانٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "د خ ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "د خ ن",
        "waznEnglish": "smoke",
        "waznTlit": "dāl khā nūn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَدَعَا",
        "answer": "So he called",
        "pcklId": "145",
        "rootWordId": 474,
        "tlit": "fadaʿā",
        "frequency": "212",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَدَعَا رَبَّهُ أَنَّ هَٰؤُلَاءِ قَوْمٌ مُجْرِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "د ع و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَعَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to call, to invite, to pray",
        "waznTlit": "daʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَدْعُونَ",
        "answer": "They will call",
        "pcklId": "146",
        "rootWordId": 474,
        "tlit": "yadʿūna",
        "frequency": "212",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "55",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَدْعُونَ فِيهَا بِكُلِّ فَاكِهَةٍ آمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "د ع و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "دَعَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to call, to invite, to pray",
        "waznTlit": "daʿā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَذَكَّرُونَ",
        "answer": "take heed",
        "pcklId": "144",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "yatadhakkarūna",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "58",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّمَا يَسَّرْنَاهُ بِلِسَانِكَ لَعَلَّهُمْ يَتَذَكَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَذَكَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to receive admonition",
        "waznTlit": "tadhakkara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الذِّكْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "the reminder",
        "pcklId": "186",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "l-dhik'rā",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنَّىٰ لَهُمُ الذِّكْرَىٰ وَقَدْ جَاءَهُمْ رَسُولٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذِكْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhik'rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذُقْ",
        "answer": "Taste",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 519,
        "tlit": "dhuq",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "49",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " ذُقْ إِنَّكَ أَنْتَ الْعَزِيزُ الْكَرِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ذ و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَاقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to taste",
        "waznTlit": "dhāqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَذُوقُونَ",
        "answer": "they will taste",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 519,
        "tlit": "yadhūqūna",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَذُوقُونَ فِيهَا الْمَوْتَ إِلَّا الْمَوْتَةَ الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَاقُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to taste",
        "waznTlit": "dhāqu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَأْسِهِ",
        "answer": "his head",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 521,
        "tlit": "rasihi",
        "frequency": "18",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ صُبُّوا فَوْقَ رَأْسِهِ مِنْ عَذَابِ الْحَمِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ر أ س",
        "waznEnglish": "your heads",
        "waznTlit": "rā hamza sīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "776",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " رَحْمَةً مِنْ رَبِّكَ إِنَّهُ هُوَ السَّمِيعُ الْعَلِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّ",
        "answer": "Lord",
        "pcklId": "777",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbi",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ مُوقِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبُّكُمْ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "778",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbukum",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ يُحْيِي وَيُمِيتُ رَبُّكُمْ وَرَبُّ آبَائِكُمُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَرَبُّ",
        "answer": "and (the) Lord",
        "pcklId": "779",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "warabbu",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ يُحْيِي وَيُمِيتُ رَبُّكُمْ وَرَبُّ آبَائِكُمُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبَّنَا",
        "answer": "Our Lord",
        "pcklId": "780",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbanā",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبَّنَا اكْشِفْ عَنَّا الْعَذَابَ إِنَّا مُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِرَبِّي",
        "answer": "with my Lord",
        "pcklId": "781",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "birabbī",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنِّي عُذْتُ بِرَبِّي وَرَبِّكُمْ أَنْ تَرْجُمُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَرَبِّكُمْ",
        "answer": "and your Lord",
        "pcklId": "782",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "warabbikum",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنِّي عُذْتُ بِرَبِّي وَرَبِّكُمْ أَنْ تَرْجُمُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبَّهُ",
        "answer": "his Lord",
        "pcklId": "783",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbahu",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَدَعَا رَبَّهُ أَنَّ هَٰؤُلَاءِ قَوْمٌ مُجْرِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "784",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "57",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَضْلًا مِنْ رَبِّكَ ذَٰلِكَ هُوَ الْفَوْزُ الْعَظِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَرْجُمُونِ",
        "answer": "you stone me",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 539,
        "tlit": "tarjumūni",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنِّي عُذْتُ بِرَبِّي وَرَبِّكُمْ أَنْ تَرْجُمُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ج م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَجَمْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to stone",
        "waznTlit": "rajam",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَحِمَ",
        "answer": "Allah has mercy",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 544,
        "tlit": "raḥima",
        "frequency": "339",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ رَحِمَ اللَّهُ إِنَّهُ هُوَ الْعَزِيزُ الرَّحِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ر ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّحِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to have mercy",
        "waznTlit": "raḥima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَحْمَةً",
        "answer": "As Mercy",
        "pcklId": "207",
        "rootWordId": 544,
        "tlit": "raḥmatan",
        "frequency": "339",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " رَحْمَةً مِنْ رَبِّكَ إِنَّهُ هُوَ السَّمِيعُ الْعَلِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ر ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَحْمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and have mercy on us",
        "waznTlit": "raḥmat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الرَّحِيمُ",
        "answer": "the Most Merciful",
        "pcklId": "311",
        "rootWordId": 544,
        "tlit": "l-raḥīmu",
        "frequency": "339",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ رَحِمَ اللَّهُ إِنَّهُ هُوَ الْعَزِيزُ الرَّحِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ر ح م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَّحِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "and have mercy on us",
        "waznTlit": "raḥīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَسُولٌ",
        "answer": "a Messenger",
        "pcklId": "397",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "rasūlun",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنَّىٰ لَهُمُ الذِّكْرَىٰ وَقَدْ جَاءَهُمْ رَسُولٌ مُبِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَسُول",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "rasūl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَسُولٌ",
        "answer": "a Messenger",
        "pcklId": "398",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "rasūlun",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ فَتَنَّا قَبْلَهُمْ قَوْمَ فِرْعَوْنَ وَجَاءَهُمْ رَسُولٌ كَرِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَسُول",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "rasūl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَسُولٌ",
        "answer": "a Messenger",
        "pcklId": "399",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "rasūlun",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ أَدُّوا إِلَيَّ عِبَادَ اللَّهِ إِنِّي لَكُمْ رَسُولٌ أَمِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَسُول",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "rasūl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُرْسِلِينَ",
        "answer": "(ever) sending",
        "pcklId": "474",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "mur'silīna",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْرًا مِنْ عِنْدِنَا إِنَّا كُنَّا مُرْسِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُرْسِل",
        "waznEnglish": "[We] have sent you",
        "waznTlit": "mur'sil",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَارْتَقِبْ",
        "answer": "Then watch",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 575,
        "tlit": "fa-ir'taqib",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَارْتَقِبْ يَوْمَ تَأْتِي السَّمَاءُ بِدُخَانٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر ق ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱرْتَقِبْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to watch",
        "waznTlit": "ir'taqib",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَارْتَقِبْ",
        "answer": "So watch",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 575,
        "tlit": "fa-ir'taqib",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "59",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَارْتَقِبْ إِنَّهُمْ مُرْتَقِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ق ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱرْتَقِبْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to watch",
        "waznTlit": "ir'taqib",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُرْتَقِبُونَ",
        "answer": "(too are) watching",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 575,
        "tlit": "mur'taqibūna",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "59",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَارْتَقِبْ إِنَّهُمْ مُرْتَقِبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ق ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّرْتَقِبُون",
        "waznEnglish": "they do not regard (the ties)",
        "waznTlit": "mur'taqibūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَهْوًا",
        "answer": "at rest",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 598,
        "tlit": "rahwan",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاتْرُكِ الْبَحْرَ رَهْوًا إِنَّهُمْ جُنْدٌ مُغْرَقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ر ه و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ر ه و",
        "waznEnglish": "at rest",
        "waznTlit": "rā hā wāw",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَزُرُوعٍ",
        "answer": "And cornfields",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 617,
        "tlit": "wazurūʿin",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَزُرُوعٍ وَمَقَامٍ كَرِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ز ر ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَرْع",
        "waznEnglish": "You will sow",
        "waznTlit": "zarʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الزَّقُّومِ",
        "answer": "(of) Zaqqum",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 623,
        "tlit": "l-zaqūmi",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ شَجَرَتَ الزَّقُّومِ",
        "rootWord": "ز ق م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ز ق م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) Zaqqum",
        "waznTlit": "zāy qāf mīm",
        "waznType": "Proper noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَزَوَّجْنَاهُمْ",
        "answer": "And We will marry them",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 638,
        "tlit": "wazawwajnāhum",
        "frequency": "81",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "54",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ وَزَوَّجْنَاهُمْ بِحُورٍ عِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ز و ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زُوِّجَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to marry, to be paired",
        "waznTlit": "zuwwijat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُسْرِفِينَ",
        "answer": "the transgressors",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 683,
        "tlit": "l-mus'rifīna",
        "frequency": "23",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ فِرْعَوْنَ إِنَّهُ كَانَ عَالِيًا مِنَ الْمُسْرِفِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س ر ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُسْرِف",
        "waznEnglish": "(be) extravagant",
        "waznTlit": "mus'rif",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَسْرِ",
        "answer": "Then \"Set out",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 686,
        "tlit": "fa-asri",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَسْرِ بِعِبَادِي لَيْلًا إِنَّكُمْ مُتَّبَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "س ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَسْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to travel, to take",
        "waznTlit": "asrā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِسُلْطَانٍ",
        "answer": "with an authority",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 713,
        "tlit": "bisul'ṭānin",
        "frequency": "39",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْ لَا تَعْلُوا عَلَى اللَّهِ إِنِّي آتِيكُمْ بِسُلْطَانٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ل ط",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سُلْطَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "surely He (would have) given them power",
        "waznTlit": "sul'ṭān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمِيعُ",
        "answer": "(is) the All-Hearer",
        "pcklId": "171",
        "rootWordId": 722,
        "tlit": "l-samīʿu",
        "frequency": "185",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " رَحْمَةً مِنْ رَبِّكَ إِنَّهُ هُوَ السَّمِيعُ الْعَلِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "س م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمِيع",
        "waznEnglish": "(who used to) hear",
        "waznTlit": "samīʿ",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاوَاتِ",
        "answer": "(of) the heavens",
        "pcklId": "281",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāwāti",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ مُوقِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاءُ",
        "answer": "the sky",
        "pcklId": "282",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāu",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَارْتَقِبْ يَوْمَ تَأْتِي السَّمَاءُ بِدُخَانٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاءُ",
        "answer": "the heaven",
        "pcklId": "283",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāu",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا بَكَتْ عَلَيْهِمُ السَّمَاءُ وَالْأَرْضُ وَمَا كَانُوا مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّمَاوَاتِ",
        "answer": "the heavens",
        "pcklId": "284",
        "rootWordId": 726,
        "tlit": "l-samāwāti",
        "frequency": "381",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقْنَا السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا لَاعِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "س م و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَمَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] (have) named her",
        "waznTlit": "samā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "سَوَاءِ",
        "answer": "(the) midst",
        "pcklId": "71",
        "rootWordId": 747,
        "tlit": "sawāi",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " خُذُوهُ فَاعْتِلُوهُ إِلَىٰ سَوَاءِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "س و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَوَآء",
        "waznEnglish": "was leveled",
        "waznTlit": "sawā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَجَرَتَ",
        "answer": "(the) tree",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 757,
        "tlit": "shajarata",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "43",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ شَجَرَتَ الزَّقُّومِ",
        "rootWord": "ش ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَجَرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "arises",
        "waznTlit": "shajarat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَكٍّ",
        "answer": "doubt ",
        "pcklId": "14",
        "rootWordId": 791,
        "tlit": "shakkin",
        "frequency": "15",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ هُمْ فِي شَكٍّ يَلْعَبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ك ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ش ك ك",
        "waznEnglish": "doubt",
        "waznTlit": "shīn kāf kāf",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "شَيْئًا",
        "answer": "anything",
        "pcklId": "466",
        "rootWordId": 810,
        "tlit": "shayan",
        "frequency": "519",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ لَا يُغْنِي مَوْلًى عَنْ مَوْلًى شَيْئًا وَلَا هُمْ يُنْصَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ش ي أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "شَىْء",
        "waznEnglish": "had willed",
        "waznTlit": "shay",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "صُبُّوا",
        "answer": "pour",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 816,
        "tlit": "ṣubbū",
        "frequency": "5",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ صُبُّوا فَوْقَ رَأْسِهِ مِنْ عَذَابِ الْحَمِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَبَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to pour",
        "waznTlit": "ṣabba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَادِقِينَ",
        "answer": "truthful",
        "pcklId": "115",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "ṣādiqīna",
        "frequency": "155",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأْتُوا بِآبَائِنَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَادِق",
        "waznEnglish": "are true",
        "waznTlit": "ṣādiq",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "طَعَامُ",
        "answer": "(Will be) food",
        "pcklId": "34",
        "rootWordId": 911,
        "tlit": "ṭaʿāmu",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "44",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " طَعَامُ الْأَثِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ط ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَعَام",
        "waznEnglish": "taste it",
        "waznTlit": "ṭaʿām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِبَادَ",
        "answer": "(the) servants",
        "pcklId": "249",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "ʿibāda",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَنْ أَدُّوا إِلَيَّ عِبَادَ اللَّهِ إِنِّي لَكُمْ رَسُولٌ أَمِينٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِعِبَادِي",
        "answer": "with My slaves",
        "pcklId": "250",
        "rootWordId": 948,
        "tlit": "biʿibādī",
        "frequency": "275",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَسْرِ بِعِبَادِي لَيْلًا إِنَّكُمْ مُتَّبَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ب د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَبْد",
        "waznEnglish": "we worship",
        "waznTlit": "ʿabd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاعْتِلُوهُ",
        "answer": "and drag him",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 955,
        "tlit": "fa-iʿ'tilūhu",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "47",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " خُذُوهُ فَاعْتِلُوهُ إِلَىٰ سَوَاءِ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ت ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱعْتِلُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to drag",
        "waznTlit": "iʿ'tilu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابٌ",
        "answer": "(will be) a punishment",
        "pcklId": "299",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhābun",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَغْشَى النَّاسَ هَٰذَا عَذَابٌ أَلِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَذَابَ",
        "answer": "the punishment",
        "pcklId": "300",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "l-ʿadhāba",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبَّنَا اكْشِفْ عَنَّا الْعَذَابَ إِنَّا مُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَذَابِ",
        "answer": "the punishment",
        "pcklId": "301",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "l-ʿadhābi",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَاشِفُو الْعَذَابِ قَلِيلًا إِنَّكُمْ عَائِدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَذَابِ",
        "answer": "the punishment",
        "pcklId": "302",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "l-ʿadhābi",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ نَجَّيْنَا بَنِي إِسْرَائِيلَ مِنَ الْعَذَابِ الْمُهِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابِ",
        "answer": "(the) punishment",
        "pcklId": "303",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhābi",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ صُبُّوا فَوْقَ رَأْسِهِ مِنْ عَذَابِ الْحَمِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَذَابَ",
        "answer": "(from the) punishment",
        "pcklId": "304",
        "rootWordId": 968,
        "tlit": "ʿadhāba",
        "frequency": "373",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَذُوقُونَ فِيهَا الْمَوْتَ إِلَّا الْمَوْتَةَ الْأُولَىٰ وَوَقَاهُمْ عَذَابَ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَذَاب",
        "waznEnglish": "and He will punish",
        "waznTlit": "ʿadhāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَزِيزُ",
        "answer": "(is) the All-Mighty",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 982,
        "tlit": "l-ʿazīzu",
        "frequency": "119",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "42",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَّا مَنْ رَحِمَ اللَّهُ إِنَّهُ هُوَ الْعَزِيزُ الرَّحِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ز ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَزِيز",
        "waznEnglish": "and he overpowered me",
        "waznTlit": "ʿazīz",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَزِيزُ",
        "answer": "the mighty",
        "pcklId": "60",
        "rootWordId": 982,
        "tlit": "l-ʿazīzu",
        "frequency": "119",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "49",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " ذُقْ إِنَّكَ أَنْتَ الْعَزِيزُ الْكَرِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ز ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَزِيز",
        "waznEnglish": "and he overpowered me",
        "waznTlit": "ʿazīz",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاعْتَزِلُونِ",
        "answer": "then leave me alone",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 983,
        "tlit": "fa-iʿ'tazilūni",
        "frequency": "10",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنْ لَمْ تُؤْمِنُوا لِي فَاعْتَزِلُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱعْتَزَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to withdraw, to leave, to keep away",
        "waznTlit": "iʿ'tazala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَظِيمُ",
        "answer": "the great",
        "pcklId": "90",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "l-ʿaẓīmu",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "57",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " فَضْلًا مِنْ رَبِّكَ ذَٰلِكَ هُوَ الْفَوْزُ الْعَظِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "answer": "know",
        "pcklId": "317",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "yaʿlamūna",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا خَلَقْنَاهُمَا إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ وَلَٰكِنَّ أَكْثَرَهُمْ لَا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalima",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "answer": "the worlds",
        "pcklId": "539",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "l-ʿālamīna",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدِ اخْتَرْنَاهُمْ عَلَىٰ عِلْمٍ عَلَى الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَٰلَمِين",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿālamīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِلْمٍ",
        "answer": "knowledge",
        "pcklId": "644",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "ʿil'min",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدِ اخْتَرْنَاهُمْ عَلَىٰ عِلْمٍ عَلَى الْعَالَمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِلْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿil'm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَلِيمُ",
        "answer": "the All-Knower",
        "pcklId": "750",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "l-ʿalīmu",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " رَحْمَةً مِنْ رَبِّكَ إِنَّهُ هُوَ السَّمِيعُ الْعَلِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُعَلَّمٌ",
        "answer": "One taught",
        "pcklId": "853",
        "rootWordId": 1016,
        "tlit": "muʿallamun",
        "frequency": "854",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ تَوَلَّوْا عَنْهُ وَقَالُوا مُعَلَّمٌ مَجْنُونٌ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُعَلَّم",
        "waznEnglish": "they know",
        "waznTlit": "muʿallam",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَعْلُوا",
        "answer": "exalt yourselves",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 1018,
        "tlit": "taʿlū",
        "frequency": "70",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَنْ لَا تَعْلُوا عَلَى اللَّهِ إِنِّي آتِيكُمْ بِسُلْطَانٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَعَٰلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be exalted, to be high",
        "waznTlit": "taʿālā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَالِيًا",
        "answer": "arrogant",
        "pcklId": "63",
        "rootWordId": 1018,
        "tlit": "ʿāliyan",
        "frequency": "70",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ فِرْعَوْنَ إِنَّهُ كَانَ عَالِيًا مِنَ الْمُسْرِفِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَالِي",
        "waznEnglish": "and Exalted",
        "waznTlit": "ʿālī",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِنْدِنَا",
        "answer": "Us",
        "pcklId": "193",
        "rootWordId": 1028,
        "tlit": "ʿindinā",
        "frequency": "201",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْرًا مِنْ عِنْدِنَا إِنَّا كُنَّا مُرْسِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ن د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِند",
        "waznEnglish": "with",
        "waznTlit": "ʿind",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَائِدُونَ",
        "answer": "(will) return",
        "pcklId": "62",
        "rootWordId": 1035,
        "tlit": "ʿāidūna",
        "frequency": "63",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَاشِفُو الْعَذَابِ قَلِيلًا إِنَّكُمْ عَائِدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ع و د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَآئِدُون",
        "waznEnglish": "repeated",
        "waznTlit": "ʿāidūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "عُذْتُ",
        "answer": "[I] seek refuge",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1036,
        "tlit": "ʿudh'tu",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَإِنِّي عُذْتُ بِرَبِّي وَرَبِّكُمْ أَنْ تَرْجُمُونِ",
        "rootWord": "ع و ذ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عُذْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to seek refuge",
        "waznTlit": "ʿudh",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِينٍ",
        "answer": "(to) companions with beautiful eyes",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1046,
        "tlit": "ʿīnin",
        "frequency": "65",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "54",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ وَزَوَّجْنَاهُمْ بِحُورٍ عِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عِين",
        "waznEnglish": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "waznTlit": "ʿīn",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَعُيُونٍ",
        "answer": "and springs",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 1046,
        "tlit": "waʿuyūnin",
        "frequency": "65",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " كَمْ تَرَكُوا مِنْ جَنَّاتٍ وَعُيُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَعُيُونٍ",
        "answer": "and springs",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 1046,
        "tlit": "waʿuyūnin",
        "frequency": "65",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "52",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فِي جَنَّاتٍ وَعُيُونٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَيْن",
        "waznEnglish": "(having) beautiful eyes",
        "waznTlit": "ʿayn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُغْرَقُونَ",
        "answer": "(to be) drowned",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 1057,
        "tlit": "mugh'raqūna",
        "frequency": "23",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " وَاتْرُكِ الْبَحْرَ رَهْوًا إِنَّهُمْ جُنْدٌ مُغْرَقُونَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ر ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّغْرَقُون",
        "waznEnglish": "and We drowned",
        "waznTlit": "mugh'raqūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَغْشَى",
        "answer": "Enveloping",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 1064,
        "tlit": "yaghshā",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَغْشَى النَّاسَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ش و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَشِيَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cover",
        "waznTlit": "ghashiya",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَغْلِي",
        "answer": "it will boil",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1080,
        "tlit": "yaghlī",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَالْمُهْلِ يَغْلِي فِي الْبُطُونِ",
        "rootWord": "غ ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَغْلِى",
        "waznEnglish": "to boil",
        "waznTlit": "yaghlī",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَغَلْيِ",
        "answer": "Like boiling",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1080,
        "tlit": "kaghalyi",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "46",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " كَغَلْيِ الْحَمِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "غ ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "غَلْى",
        "waznEnglish": "it will boil",
        "waznTlit": "ghal",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُغْنِي",
        "answer": "will avail",
        "pcklId": "30",
        "rootWordId": 1086,
        "tlit": "yugh'nī",
        "frequency": "73",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ لَا يُغْنِي مَوْلًى عَنْ مَوْلًى شَيْئًا وَلَا هُمْ يُنْصَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "غ ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَغْنَتْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to avail, to enrich",
        "waznTlit": "aghnat",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَتَنَّا",
        "answer": "We tried",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 1105,
        "tlit": "fatannā",
        "frequency": "60",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ فَتَنَّا قَبْلَهُمْ قَوْمَ فِرْعَوْنَ وَجَاءَهُمْ رَسُولٌ كَرِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ف ت ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَتَنُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to persecute, to test, to try",
        "waznTlit": "fatanu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُفْرَقُ",
        "answer": "is made distinct",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1124,
        "tlit": "yuf'raqu",
        "frequency": "72",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فِيهَا يُفْرَقُ كُلُّ أَمْرٍ حَكِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ف ر ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَرَقْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to divide",
        "waznTlit": "faraq",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفَصْلِ",
        "answer": "(the) Day of Judgment",
        "pcklId": "28",
        "rootWordId": 1135,
        "tlit": "l-faṣli",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ يَوْمَ الْفَصْلِ مِيقَاتُهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ص ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَصْل",
        "waznEnglish": "set out",
        "waznTlit": "faṣl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَضْلًا",
        "answer": "A Bounty",
        "pcklId": "88",
        "rootWordId": 1139,
        "tlit": "faḍlan",
        "frequency": "104",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "57",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَضْلًا مِنْ رَبِّكَ ذَٰلِكَ هُوَ الْفَوْزُ الْعَظِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ف ض ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَضْل",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] preferred you",
        "waznTlit": "faḍl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاكِهَةٍ",
        "answer": "(of) fruit",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1150,
        "tlit": "fākihatin",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "55",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَدْعُونَ فِيهَا بِكُلِّ فَاكِهَةٍ آمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ك ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَٰكِهَة",
        "waznEnglish": "wondering",
        "waznTlit": "fākihat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاكِهِينَ",
        "answer": "take delight",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 1150,
        "tlit": "fākihīna",
        "frequency": "19",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَعْمَةٍ كَانُوا فِيهَا فَاكِهِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ف ك ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَٰكِهِين",
        "waznEnglish": "wondering",
        "waznTlit": "fākihīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفَوْزُ",
        "answer": "(will be) the success",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 1162,
        "tlit": "l-fawzu",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "57",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " فَضْلًا مِنْ رَبِّكَ ذَٰلِكَ هُوَ الْفَوْزُ الْعَظِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ف و ز",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَوْز",
        "waznEnglish": "he is successful",
        "waznTlit": "fawz",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَوْقَ",
        "answer": "over",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 1164,
        "tlit": "fawqa",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "48",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ صُبُّوا فَوْقَ رَأْسِهِ مِنْ عَذَابِ الْحَمِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "ف و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَوْق",
        "waznEnglish": "he recovered",
        "waznTlit": "fawq",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَبْلِهِمْ",
        "answer": "before them",
        "pcklId": "203",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "qablihim",
        "frequency": "294",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " أَهُمْ خَيْرٌ أَمْ قَوْمُ تُبَّعٍ وَالَّذِينَ مِنْ قَبْلِهِمْ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَبْل",
        "waznEnglish": "will be accepted",
        "waznTlit": "qabl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَبْلَهُمْ",
        "answer": "before them",
        "pcklId": "262",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "qablahum",
        "frequency": "294",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ فَتَنَّا قَبْلَهُمْ قَوْمَ فِرْعَوْنَ وَجَاءَهُمْ رَسُولٌ كَرِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَبْل",
        "waznEnglish": "will be accepted",
        "waznTlit": "qabl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "answer": "facing each other",
        "pcklId": "291",
        "rootWordId": 1174,
        "tlit": "mutaqābilīna",
        "frequency": "294",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "53",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَلْبَسُونَ مِنْ سُنْدُسٍ وَإِسْتَبْرَقٍ مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّتَقَٰبِلِين",
        "waznEnglish": "will be accepted",
        "waznTlit": "mutaqābilīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VI)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَلِيلًا",
        "answer": "a little",
        "pcklId": "69",
        "rootWordId": 1225,
        "tlit": "qalīlan",
        "frequency": "76",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَاشِفُو الْعَذَابِ قَلِيلًا إِنَّكُمْ عَائِدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَلِيل",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) little",
        "waznTlit": "qalīl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقَالُوا",
        "answer": "and said",
        "pcklId": "1444",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "waqālū",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ تَوَلَّوْا عَنْهُ وَقَالُوا مُعَلَّمٌ مَجْنُونٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيَقُولُونَ",
        "answer": "surely, they say",
        "pcklId": "1445",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "layaqūlūna",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ هَٰؤُلَاءِ لَيَقُولُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(the) people",
        "pcklId": "434",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "qawma",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ فَتَنَّا قَبْلَهُمْ قَوْمَ فِرْعَوْنَ وَجَاءَهُمْ رَسُولٌ كَرِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَوْمٌ",
        "answer": "(are) a people",
        "pcklId": "435",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "qawmun",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَدَعَا رَبَّهُ أَنَّ هَٰؤُلَاءِ قَوْمٌ مُجْرِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَوْمًا",
        "answer": "(for) a people",
        "pcklId": "436",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "qawman",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ وَأَوْرَثْنَاهَا قَوْمًا آخَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَوْمُ",
        "answer": "(the) people",
        "pcklId": "437",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "qawmu",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَهُمْ خَيْرٌ أَمْ قَوْمُ تُبَّعٍ وَالَّذِينَ مِنْ قَبْلِهِمْ أَهْلَكْنَاهُمْ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَوْم",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qawm",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَمَقَامٍ",
        "answer": "and places",
        "pcklId": "579",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "wamaqāmin",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَزُرُوعٍ وَمَقَامٍ كَرِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَقَام",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "maqām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَقَامٍ",
        "answer": "a place",
        "pcklId": "580",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "maqāmin",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "51",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُتَّقِينَ فِي مَقَامٍ أَمِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَقَام",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "maqām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكُبْرَىٰ",
        "answer": "the greatest",
        "pcklId": "90",
        "rootWordId": 1254,
        "tlit": "l-kub'rā",
        "frequency": "161",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ نَبْطِشُ الْبَطْشَةَ الْكُبْرَىٰ إِنَّا مُنْتَقِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ب ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُبْرَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "they will grow up",
        "waznTlit": "kub'rā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْكِتَابِ",
        "answer": "By the Book",
        "pcklId": "271",
        "rootWordId": 1256,
        "tlit": "wal-kitābi",
        "frequency": "319",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْكِتَابِ الْمُبِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ت ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كِتَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "write",
        "waznTlit": "kitāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَكْثَرَهُمْ",
        "answer": "most of them",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 1259,
        "tlit": "aktharahum",
        "frequency": "167",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " مَا خَلَقْنَاهُمَا إِلَّا بِالْحَقِّ وَلَٰكِنَّ أَكْثَرَهُمْ لَا يَعْلَمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ث ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَكْثَر",
        "waznEnglish": "much ",
        "waznTlit": "akthar",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَرِيمٌ",
        "answer": "noble",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 1267,
        "tlit": "karīmun",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ فَتَنَّا قَبْلَهُمْ قَوْمَ فِرْعَوْنَ وَجَاءَهُمْ رَسُولٌ كَرِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَرِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "You have honored",
        "waznTlit": "karīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَرِيمٍ",
        "answer": "noble",
        "pcklId": "26",
        "rootWordId": 1267,
        "tlit": "karīmin",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَزُرُوعٍ وَمَقَامٍ كَرِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَرِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "You have honored",
        "waznTlit": "karīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْكَرِيمُ",
        "answer": "the noble",
        "pcklId": "27",
        "rootWordId": 1267,
        "tlit": "l-karīmu",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "49",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " ذُقْ إِنَّكَ أَنْتَ الْعَزِيزُ الْكَرِيمُ",
        "rootWord": "ك ر م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَرِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "You have honored",
        "waznTlit": "karīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Adjective)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اكْشِفْ",
        "answer": "Remove",
        "pcklId": "11",
        "rootWordId": 1275,
        "tlit": "ik'shif",
        "frequency": "20",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبَّنَا اكْشِفْ عَنَّا الْعَذَابَ إِنَّا مُؤْمِنُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ش ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَشَفَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to remove, to uncover",
        "waznTlit": "kashafa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَاشِفُو",
        "answer": "(will) remove",
        "pcklId": "17",
        "rootWordId": 1275,
        "tlit": "kāshifū",
        "frequency": "20",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا كَاشِفُو الْعَذَابِ قَلِيلًا إِنَّكُمْ عَائِدُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ش ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَاشِف",
        "waznEnglish": "and He would remove",
        "waznTlit": "kāshif",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُلُّ",
        "answer": "every",
        "pcklId": "299",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "kullu",
        "frequency": "377",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فِيهَا يُفْرَقُ كُلُّ أَمْرٍ حَكِيمٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِكُلِّ",
        "answer": "for every (kind)",
        "pcklId": "300",
        "rootWordId": 1288,
        "tlit": "bikulli",
        "frequency": "377",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "55",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَدْعُونَ فِيهَا بِكُلِّ فَاكِهَةٍ آمِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كُلّ",
        "waznEnglish": "(is) a burden",
        "waznTlit": "kull",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنَّا",
        "answer": "[We] are",
        "pcklId": "1163",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kunnā",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَنْزَلْنَاهُ فِي لَيْلَةٍ مُبَارَكَةٍ إِنَّا كُنَّا مُنْذِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنَّا",
        "answer": "[We] are",
        "pcklId": "1164",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kunnā",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَمْرًا مِنْ عِنْدِنَا إِنَّا كُنَّا مُرْسِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you are",
        "pcklId": "1165",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ مُوقِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they used to",
        "pcklId": "1166",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَعْمَةٍ كَانُوا فِيهَا فَاكِهِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "they were",
        "pcklId": "1167",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا بَكَتْ عَلَيْهِمُ السَّمَاءُ وَالْأَرْضُ وَمَا كَانُوا مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "was",
        "pcklId": "1168",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " مِنْ فِرْعَوْنَ إِنَّهُ كَانَ عَالِيًا مِنَ الْمُسْرِفِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you are",
        "pcklId": "1169",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأْتُوا بِآبَائِنَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ صَادِقِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانُوا",
        "answer": "were",
        "pcklId": "1170",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kānū",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "11",
        "arabicAyah": " أَهْلَكْنَاهُمْ إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا مُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كُنْتُمْ",
        "answer": "you used to",
        "pcklId": "1171",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kuntum",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ هَٰذَا مَا كُنْتُمْ بِهِ تَمْتَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَلْبَسُونَ",
        "answer": "Wearing garments",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1315,
        "tlit": "yalbasūna",
        "frequency": "23",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "53",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَلْبَسُونَ مِنْ سُنْدُسٍ وَإِسْتَبْرَقٍ مُتَقَابِلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ب س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَبَسْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to obscure, to confuse, to mix, to wear",
        "waznTlit": "labas",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِلِسَانِكَ",
        "answer": "in your tongue",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1330,
        "tlit": "bilisānika",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "58",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّمَا يَسَّرْنَاهُ بِلِسَانِكَ لَعَلَّهُمْ يَتَذَكَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ل س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل س ن",
        "waznEnglish": "their tongues",
        "waznTlit": "lām sīn nūn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَلْعَبُونَ",
        "answer": "playing",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1333,
        "tlit": "yalʿabūna",
        "frequency": "20",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ هُمْ فِي شَكٍّ يَلْعَبُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ع ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَلْعَبْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to play",
        "waznTlit": "yalʿab",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَاعِبِينَ",
        "answer": "(in) play",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1333,
        "tlit": "lāʿibīna",
        "frequency": "20",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " وَمَا خَلَقْنَا السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضَ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا لَاعِبِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ع ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَٰعِبِين",
        "waznEnglish": "playing",
        "waznTlit": "lāʿibīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيْلًا",
        "answer": "(by) night",
        "pcklId": "59",
        "rootWordId": 1364,
        "tlit": "laylan",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَسْرِ بِعِبَادِي لَيْلًا إِنَّكُمْ مُتَّبَعُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَيْل",
        "waznEnglish": "of the night",
        "waznTlit": "layl",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لَيْلَةٍ",
        "answer": "a Night",
        "pcklId": "87",
        "rootWordId": 1364,
        "tlit": "laylatin",
        "frequency": "92",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَنْزَلْنَاهُ فِي لَيْلَةٍ مُبَارَكَةٍ إِنَّا كُنَّا مُنْذِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَيْلَة",
        "waznEnglish": "of the night",
        "waznTlit": "laylat",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَمْتَرُونَ",
        "answer": "doubt",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1387,
        "tlit": "tamtarūna",
        "frequency": "20",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "50",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ هَٰذَا مَا كُنْتُمْ بِهِ تَمْتَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "م ر ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَمْتَرُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to dispute, to doubt",
        "waznTlit": "yamtaru",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَالْمُهْلِ",
        "answer": "Like the murky oil",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1422,
        "tlit": "kal-muh'li",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "45",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " كَالْمُهْلِ يَغْلِي فِي الْبُطُونِ",
        "rootWord": "م ه ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُهْل",
        "waznEnglish": "and allow them respite ",
        "waznTlit": "muh'l",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَيُمِيتُ",
        "answer": "and causes death",
        "pcklId": "54",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "wayumītu",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا هُوَ يُحْيِي وَيُمِيتُ رَبُّكُمْ وَرَبُّ آبَائِكُمُ الْأَوَّلِينَ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمَاتَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cause death",
        "waznTlit": "amāta",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَوْتَ",
        "answer": "the death",
        "pcklId": "103",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "l-mawta",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَذُوقُونَ فِيهَا الْمَوْتَ إِلَّا الْمَوْتَةَ الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَوْت",
        "waznEnglish": "(should) you die",
        "waznTlit": "mawt",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَوْتَتُنَا",
        "answer": "our death",
        "pcklId": "114",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "mawtatunā",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هِيَ إِلَّا مَوْتَتُنَا الْأُولَىٰ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمُنْشَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَوْتَت",
        "waznEnglish": "(should) you die",
        "waznTlit": "mawtat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَوْتَةَ",
        "answer": "the death",
        "pcklId": "115",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "l-mawtata",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَذُوقُونَ فِيهَا الْمَوْتَ إِلَّا الْمَوْتَةَ الْأُولَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَوْتَت",
        "waznEnglish": "(should) you die",
        "waznTlit": "mawtat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَجَّيْنَا",
        "answer": "We saved",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 1445,
        "tlit": "najjaynā",
        "frequency": "84",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ نَجَّيْنَا بَنِي إِسْرَائِيلَ مِنَ الْعَذَابِ الْمُهِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ج و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَجَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to save, to deliver",
        "waznTlit": "najjā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنْذِرِينَ",
        "answer": "(ever) warning",
        "pcklId": "121",
        "rootWordId": 1456,
        "tlit": "mundhirīna",
        "frequency": "130",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَنْزَلْنَاهُ فِي لَيْلَةٍ مُبَارَكَةٍ إِنَّا كُنَّا مُنْذِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنذِر",
        "waznEnglish": "you vow",
        "waznTlit": "mundhir",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَنْزَلْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "revealed it",
        "pcklId": "232",
        "rootWordId": 1460,
        "tlit": "anzalnāhu",
        "frequency": "293",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّا أَنْزَلْنَاهُ فِي لَيْلَةٍ مُبَارَكَةٍ إِنَّا كُنَّا مُنْذِرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ز ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَنزَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send down, to reveal",
        "waznTlit": "anzala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِمُنْشَرِينَ",
        "answer": "(will be) raised again",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1471,
        "tlit": "bimunsharīna",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنْ هِيَ إِلَّا مَوْتَتُنَا الْأُولَىٰ وَمَا نَحْنُ بِمُنْشَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ش ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنشَرِين",
        "waznEnglish": "Will spread",
        "waznTlit": "munsharīn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُنْصَرُونَ",
        "answer": "will be helped",
        "pcklId": "46",
        "rootWordId": 1477,
        "tlit": "yunṣarūna",
        "frequency": "158",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "10",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ لَا يُغْنِي مَوْلًى عَنْ مَوْلًى شَيْئًا وَلَا هُمْ يُنْصَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَصَرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to help",
        "waznTlit": "naṣara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "answer": "given respite",
        "pcklId": "122",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "munẓarīna",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " فَمَا بَكَتْ عَلَيْهِمُ السَّمَاءُ وَالْأَرْضُ وَمَا كَانُوا مُنْظَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنظَرُون",
        "waznEnglish": "(were) looking",
        "waznTlit": "munẓarūn",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَنَعْمَةٍ",
        "answer": "And pleasant things",
        "pcklId": "120",
        "rootWordId": 1492,
        "tlit": "wanaʿmatin",
        "frequency": "140",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَنَعْمَةٍ كَانُوا فِيهَا فَاكِهِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ع م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّعْمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "then good",
        "waznTlit": "naʿmat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُنْتَقِمُونَ",
        "answer": "(will) take retribution",
        "pcklId": "16",
        "rootWordId": 1512,
        "tlit": "muntaqimūna",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ نَبْطِشُ الْبَطْشَةَ الْكُبْرَىٰ إِنَّا مُنْتَقِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ق م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُنتَقِمُون",
        "waznEnglish": "you resent",
        "waznTlit": "muntaqimūn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "النَّاسَ",
        "answer": "the people",
        "pcklId": "217",
        "rootWordId": 1530,
        "tlit": "l-nāsa",
        "frequency": "241",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَغْشَى النَّاسَ هَٰذَا عَذَابٌ أَلِيمٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن و س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن و س",
        "waznEnglish": "the people",
        "waznTlit": "nūn wāw sīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَهْلَكْنَاهُمْ",
        "answer": "We destroyed them",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 1559,
        "tlit": "ahlaknāhum",
        "frequency": "68",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "9",
        "arabicAyah": " أَهْلَكْنَاهُمْ إِنَّهُمْ كَانُوا مُجْرِمِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ه ل ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَهْلَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to destroy",
        "waznTlit": "ahlaka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُهِينِ",
        "answer": "the humiliating",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 1570,
        "tlit": "l-muhīni",
        "frequency": "26",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَقَدْ نَجَّيْنَا بَنِي إِسْرَائِيلَ مِنَ الْعَذَابِ الْمُهِينِ",
        "rootWord": "ه و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّهِين",
        "waznEnglish": "Allah humiliates",
        "waznTlit": "muhīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV) (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَوْرَثْنَاهَا",
        "answer": "And We made it (an) inherit(ance)",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 1601,
        "tlit": "wa-awrathnāhā",
        "frequency": "35",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَذَٰلِكَ وَأَوْرَثْنَاهَا قَوْمًا آخَرِينَ",
        "rootWord": "و ر ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوْرَثَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make inherit",
        "waznTlit": "awratha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مِيقَاتُهُمْ",
        "answer": "(is) an appointed term for them",
        "pcklId": "6",
        "rootWordId": 1635,
        "tlit": "mīqātuhum",
        "frequency": "13",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ يَوْمَ الْفَصْلِ مِيقَاتُهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مِيقَٰت",
        "waznEnglish": "are gathered to their appointed time",
        "waznTlit": "mīqāt",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَوَقَاهُمْ",
        "answer": "And He will protect them",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "wawaqāhum",
        "frequency": "258",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "56",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا يَذُوقُونَ فِيهَا الْمَوْتَ إِلَّا الْمَوْتَةَ الْأُولَىٰ وَوَقَاهُمْ عَذَابَ الْجَحِيمِ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَقَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to save, to protect",
        "waznTlit": "waqā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُتَّقِينَ",
        "answer": "the righteous",
        "pcklId": "247",
        "rootWordId": 1641,
        "tlit": "l-mutaqīna",
        "frequency": "258",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "51",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ الْمُتَّقِينَ فِي مَقَامٍ أَمِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "و ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُتَّقِين",
        "waznEnglish": "and save us",
        "waznTlit": "muttaqīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَوَلَّوْا",
        "answer": "they turned away",
        "pcklId": "84",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "tawallaw",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ تَوَلَّوْا عَنْهُ وَقَالُوا مُعَلَّمٌ مَجْنُونٌ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "tawallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَوْلًى",
        "answer": "a relation",
        "pcklId": "135",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "mawlan",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ لَا يُغْنِي مَوْلًى",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَوْلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "(are) close to you",
        "waznTlit": "mawlā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَوْلًى",
        "answer": "a relation",
        "pcklId": "136",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "mawlan",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " عَنْ مَوْلًى شَيْئًا وَلَا هُمْ يُنْصَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَوْلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "(are) close to you",
        "waznTlit": "mawlā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسَّرْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "We have made it easy",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1658,
        "tlit": "yassarnāhu",
        "frequency": "44",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "58",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِنَّمَا يَسَّرْنَاهُ بِلِسَانِكَ لَعَلَّهُمْ يَتَذَكَّرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ي س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَسَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make easy",
        "waznTlit": "yassara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مُوقِنِينَ",
        "answer": "certain",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 1660,
        "tlit": "mūqinīna",
        "frequency": "28",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "8",
        "arabicAyah": " رَبِّ السَّمَاوَاتِ وَالْأَرْضِ وَمَا بَيْنَهُمَا إِنْ كُنْتُمْ مُوقِنِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ي ق ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُّوقِنِين",
        "waznEnglish": "firmly believe",
        "waznTlit": "mūqinīn",
        "waznType": "Active participle (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(for the) Day",
        "pcklId": "242",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَارْتَقِبْ يَوْمَ تَأْتِي السَّمَاءُ بِدُخَانٍ مُبِينٍ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day",
        "pcklId": "243",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ نَبْطِشُ الْبَطْشَةَ الْكُبْرَىٰ إِنَّا مُنْتَقِمُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(the) Day of Judgment",
        "pcklId": "244",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ يَوْمَ الْفَصْلِ مِيقَاتُهُمْ أَجْمَعِينَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمَ",
        "answer": "(The) Day",
        "pcklId": "245",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawma",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "44",
        "ayahnum": "41",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَوْمَ لَا يُغْنِي مَوْلًى عَنْ مَوْلًى شَيْئًا وَلَا هُمْ يُنْصَرُونَ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    }
]; 
export default words;